<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>WLRN &#8211; Public Radio Biz Lab</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/wlrn/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 21:34:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/cropped-bizlab_round_wordmark_yellow-1-32x32.gif</url>
	<title>WLRN &#8211; Public Radio Biz Lab</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The BizLab Innovation Process &#038; The 2019 Station Cohort</title>
		<link>/2020/01/the-bizlab-innovation-process-the-2019-station-cohort/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joan DiMicco]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 22:23:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2019 Summit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News from the Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BizLab Methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CapRadio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LPM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WAMU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WDET]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WLRN]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2635</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[This is a summary of Opening Remarks from the BizLab Summit] WBUR BizLab&#8217;s mission is to identify and test ideas for new revenue in public radio. WBUR strongly believes that all of us in public media and nonprofit journalism need to remain vibrant and financially strong, so that we can continue to serve our mission [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>[This is a summary of Opening Remarks from the </em><a href="/summit/"><em>BizLab Summit</em></a><em>]</em></p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="2019 BizLab Summit: Experiments in New Revenue for Public Radio" width="580" height="326" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vid4IpZHNeo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<h4>WBUR BizLab&#8217;s mission is to identify and test ideas for new revenue in public radio.</h4>
<p>WBUR strongly believes that <em>all of us</em> in public media and nonprofit journalism need to remain vibrant and financially strong, so that we can continue to serve our mission of being a trusted and indispensable source of news and information. And to do that, we need to work together to identify paths forward in sustainability. And that is what BizLab&#8217;s year and this Summit is about: all of us coming together to learn, and to openly share what we’ve learned, to collectively become stronger.</p>
<p>2019 was an exciting year for us. Because of funding from CPB and Knight Foundation, BizLab was able to work with a diverse group of NPR stations across the country, all with different challenges and different opportunities. The 2019 cohort of stations were the <a href="/tag/wamu/">DCist from WAMU</a>, <a href="/tag/lpm/">Louisville Public Media</a>, <a href="/tag/wdet/">WDET from Detroit</a>, <a href="/tag/capradio/">Capital Public Radio from Sacramento</a>, <a href="/tag/wlrn/">WLRN from Miami</a>, and <a href="/tag/vpr/">Vermont Public Radio</a>. <strong>The challenge put forth to these stations was to spend 6 months with us identifying a new path to revenue.</strong></p>
<h4>How does an organization find a new path to revenue?</h4>
<p>There are a lot of ways to launch a new revenue stream within an organization. Many of us have experience in doing this, both at our stations and in other industries.</p>
<p>One way is through acquisition of a business or expertise. For example, <a href="https://www.npr.org/about-npr/607823388/pocket-cast-acquired">NPR, WBEZ, WNYC, and This American Life acquired the podcast distribution platform Pocket Casts</a>. By acquiring a revenue-generating business in an adjacent industry (in this case podcast distribution), an organization can add a new revenue stream and valuable new assets to its portfolio: new technology, skills and expertise, and podcast consumption data insights. The acquisition of non-revenue-generating assets allows organizations to further branch off to create new products or to use the assets to increase revenue in existing revenue streams.</p>
<p>For organizations where acquisition of new products and other organizations is not a viable option, the best option for creating new revenue is by innovating internally, using the skills and resources already available to the organization. While &#8220;innovation&#8221; can be a buzzword, and R&amp;D and innovation labs can be more flash than substance, there are known methods that work: Design Thinking and Lean Startup methods are used by startups and entrepreneurs of all shapes and sizes to identify product ideas and test them quickly and efficiently. This model for new product design has been used for over a decade by both  fledging startups and top corporations.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/innovationprocess.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2638" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/innovationprocess-1024x378.png" alt="BizLab Innovation Process" width="547" height="202" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/innovationprocess-1024x378.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/innovationprocess-300x111.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/innovationprocess-768x283.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/innovationprocess-1536x567.png 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/innovationprocess.png 1578w" sizes="(max-width: 547px) 100vw, 547px" /></a></p>
<h4>But we are a mission-driven non-profit. How do the principles of product development apply here?</h4>
<p>Although we are in public media, where our content is provided as a public service, the principles of product design still apply. Even when we do not directly charge for the goods and services we provide, that doesn’t mean that the value we provide cannot be monetized. The example of corporate sponsorship is probably most clear: when corporate underwriters provide support for our station, they are receiving something of value to them: access to new customers. Our underwriters need access to our audience, and the on-air underwriting spots provides this to them.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/product-market-fit.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2639" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/product-market-fit-1024x729.png" alt="" width="495" height="352" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/product-market-fit-1024x729.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/product-market-fit-300x214.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/product-market-fit-768x547.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/product-market-fit.png 1118w" sizes="(max-width: 495px) 100vw, 495px" /></a></p>
<p>This concept of value exchange also applies to a donation. <strong>Our public radio members donate to us because of what they get when they donate.</strong> It varies per donor: some donate because it makes them feel good that they financially supported something aligned to their values. Others donate because they want the tote bag or exclusive premium — they are purchasing a good. Others donate because they want to reinforce their identity as a “public radio nerd” and be an insider. By projecting to the world that they donate, they are making it clear they are true insiders.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Self-declared Public Radio Nerds on Instagram</em><br />
<img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2651" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/IG-publicradionerd-1024x1024.jpg" alt="" width="359" height="359" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/IG-publicradionerd-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/IG-publicradionerd-300x300.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/IG-publicradionerd-150x150.jpg 150w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/IG-publicradionerd-768x768.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/IG-publicradionerd-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/IG-publicradionerd.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 359px) 100vw, 359px" /></p>
<p><strong style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">The point is that new revenue comes from us providing new value to our audience, and asking them to pay for it. And the tighter the connection we can tie between the value we produce and the benefit people get from it, the more likely it is that the audience or user will contribute, by taking action and paying. </strong></p>
<h4><strong style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">The first step of product development is identifying a problem people want solved</strong></h4>
<p>With the six BizLab stations, we set out to understand the values, needs and wants of the target customers of their ideas. Through interviews, focus groups, surveys, and data analysis, each team spent two months focusing on listening and learning about what matters to the audiences, companies, and external stakeholders who interact with public media. Several themes emerged. From audiences, we heard statements like:</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>&#8220;I need my news delivered when and how I consume it.&#8221;</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>&#8220;I want to be up to date on what is going on near me.&#8221;</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>&#8220;I want the latest news on the topic I am passionate about.&#8221;</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>&#8220;I want access to exclusive events.&#8221;</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>&#8220;I want to be in the know.&#8221;</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>These needs and wants speak volumes to personalizing our delivery of news and information, on their terms and on their platforms. If we make their lives easier, we will have earned a place in their news landscape. From companies and potential sponsors we heard:</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>&#8220;I want to connect with people who care about my type of business.&#8221;</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>&#8220;I need a simple way of creating ads that work.&#8221;</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>&#8220;I need a one-stop-shop for buying ads across multiple regions.&#8221;</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>These statements reveal how complex the advertising world has become, and if we can simplify the landscape and enable connections between companies and their customers, we will be solving concrete problems for them.</p>
<h4>Cohort Station Product Ideas</h4>
<p>With these values identified, the six stations were each able to define a product around a specific need or want they could solve.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/6stations.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2637" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/6stations.png" alt="bizlab cohort" width="469" height="239" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/6stations.png 882w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/6stations-300x153.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/6stations-768x392.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 469px) 100vw, 469px" /></a></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>WAMU</strong> designed a membership for the <a href="https://dcist.com/">DCist</a>, distinct from a membership to WAMU with perks designed for the loyal DCist reader.</li>
<li><strong>Louisville Public Media</strong> launched a new membership program for <a href="https://do502.com/">Do502</a>, an events listing website, centered around exclusive events and ticket discounts, again, distinct from a membership to Louisville Public Media.</li>
<li><strong>WDET </strong>tested the product offering for small businesses in Detroit — a social media sponsored content product, designed to reach their desired customers.</li>
<li><strong>Capital Public Radio</strong> reimagining a cross-network underwriting sales product, converting a longstanding 15-second spot agreement between CapRadio and California public radio stations into a regional underwriting product, giving new access to underwriters to reach the state of California.</li>
<li><strong>WLRN </strong>created a new climate and environmental newsletter product, launching it with an eye towards it being a new membership donation channel and sponsorship opportunity.</li>
<li><strong>Vermont Public Radio </strong>focused on deeply serving Southern Vermont residents by delivering localized and targeted news on multiple platforms, to increase their engagement with VPR content and to increase donations from the region.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Lean Testing</h4>
<p>Today&#8217;s Summit will share the details of these projects through <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Slides-Lightning-Talks.pdf">lightning talks</a> and panel presentations. Because teams followed our innovation process, they <em>did not</em> launch these products immediately after determining these ideas met user needs. Instead they tested them. They each<span style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;"> created the tiniest example of what the idea was and quickly showed it to customers in as much of a real way as possible. In this way, the teams collected evidence that the idea was a good one. And sometimes it wasn&#8217;t good! But because they had moved quickly and hadn&#8217;t spent many resources on their test, the failures were quick and painless. The teams could move on, glad to have not expended more time on the idea. </span></p>
<p>Stations each went through four months of testing each idea, launching experiments as frequently as every two weeks. After each test, they refined their product idea. They continually built evidence of what was working, pivoting and changing as they learned what didn’t work.</p>
<p>Some examples of tests include: DCist and LPM asked people to join non-existent membership programs. LPM printed membership cards for the first 12 members on their office printers. WLRN posted sign-up sheets for non-existent newsletters to gauge interest in topics. WDET asked small businesses to sign up for a pilot program, simply to see if anyone would sign up. CapRadio pitched an advertising product that didn’t have a name yet. VPR asked people to register for a news &amp; brews event that ended up being cancelled. But they learned in that test that people wanted to attend.</p>
<p>These teams went out on a limb and asked potential users to take action, so that they could see if there was tangible interest in this concept. They ran small, fast tests and earned small amounts of revenue in the process, in order to determine what would work and what would not work. <strong>It was through this process that the stations identified ways of expanding existing station revenue, whether that was through entirely new products or through new donation channels, or with new content to drive new donations. </strong></p>
<h4>The Financial Results</h4>
<p>Each project has many lessons learned embedded in the details you&#8217;ll hear today. In aggregate, the projects also tell a compelling financial story. During the testing phase, stations collected $83,000 in revenue. Remember, our goal during testing wasn&#8217;t to make revenue, but to learn what was working. And it was from this testing, that each team made proposals to their stations to launch a new product, defined based on the lessons learned. <strong>And their collective revenue targets for 2020, the first year of each product, totals to $600,000.</strong> The charts below break down these numbers by product type and by station. These teams deserve applause for these results!</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/revenue-results.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2662" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/revenue-results-1024x440.png" alt="" width="750" height="322" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/revenue-results-1024x440.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/revenue-results-300x129.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/revenue-results-768x330.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/revenue-results-1536x660.png 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/revenue-results.png 1602w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></a></p>
<h4>Summit Overview</h4>
<p>This introduction gives you the basic framework of how these stations went from a challenge to find new revenue to actually finding it. They took on the role of entrepreneurs this year, and through flexibility, speed, and curiosity they found new opportunities for their stations.</p>
<p>The rest of today will be about sharing our collective discoveries of what works, what doesn’t work, and the challenges we faced. The day begins with each station telling you more about their projects and results. Then we will discuss the organizational and cultural challenges of introducing new ideas and launching new products at an organization. We have a fantastic panel on leadership and innovation. And we will wrap up the day with concrete case studies of tools and tips for using text messaging platforms and asking for podcast donations.</p>
<h4>In Conclusion</h4>
<p>Lean in today, and have conversations and capture ideas that you can apply at your own organization. This work is not easy, but it is urgent, and we are in this together.</p>
<p><strong>I want to emphasize one thing: all of us can do this. Every public radio station can identify new possibilities for revenue and quickly test and size the opportunity and choose to take it forward. </strong>When hearing about how BizLab cohort stations did it, in addition to observing what they learned, pay attention to how they did it. You can take both their lessons learned and their techniques home with you today.</p>
<p><em>[Download <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Slides-Joan-Opening-Remarks.pdf">slides from this presentation</a> or <a href="https://youtu.be/dIqNF0-vSXg">watch the video</a>.]</em></p>
<h4></h4>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Six Stations, Six Revenue Projects</title>
		<link>/2020/01/six-station-revenue-projects/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joan DiMicco]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 21:53:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2019 Summit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BizLab Experiments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News from the Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CapRadio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LPM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WAMU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WDET]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WLRN]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2721</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[BizLab stations across the country spent 2019 testing news ideas for revenue at their stations and in their communities. At the BizLab Summit, each station gave a six-minute overview of their project. Download their slides (PDF) Watch WDET, Vermont Public Radio, and WLRN&#8217;s panel discussion, followed by their lightning presentations Watch Louisville Public Media, WAMU, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/WBUR-Summit-60-giselle-scaled.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2725" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/WBUR-Summit-60-giselle-1024x683.jpg" alt="" width="750" height="500" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/WBUR-Summit-60-giselle-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/WBUR-Summit-60-giselle-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/WBUR-Summit-60-giselle-768x513.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/WBUR-Summit-60-giselle-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/WBUR-Summit-60-giselle-2048x1367.jpg 2048w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/WBUR-Summit-60-giselle-930x620.jpg 930w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></a></p>
<p>BizLab stations across the country spent 2019 testing news ideas for revenue at their stations and in their communities. At the BizLab Summit, each station gave a six-minute overview of their project.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Slides-Lightning-Talks.pdf">Download their slides (PDF)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://youtu.be/wMknsJMCuGA">Watch WDET, Vermont Public Radio, and WLRN&#8217;s panel discussion, followed by their lightning presentations</a></li>
<li><a href="https://youtu.be/XBt3ymiRn84">Watch Louisville Public Media, WAMU, and Capital Public Radio&#8217;s panel discussion, followed by their lightning presentations</a></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2733 alignnone" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/wamu-team-1024x390.png" alt="" width="475" height="181" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/wamu-team-1024x390.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/wamu-team-300x114.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/wamu-team-768x293.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/wamu-team.png 1286w" sizes="(max-width: 475px) 100vw, 475px" /></p>
<p><strong>WAMU</strong>, in Washington, D.C., acquired and revived the digital news outlet DCist in 2018, helping to fill a void in D.C.’s news ecosystem. DCist.com has a large and loyal audience, but until now the audience was not directly supporting the website.</p>
<p>DCist’s project with BizLab aimed to craft a robust and unique membership program, distinct to the brand of DCist: knowledgeable, playful, and engaging. To test the team’s assumptions, their BizLab project invited previous backers of a Kickstarter campaign to join a beta membership program. That group was used to test hypotheses about which membership benefits and offerings would resonate. A few months later, the DCist launched its membership program to the public on November 1, 2019 and has seen a heartening initial response.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2732  alignnone" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/lpm-team-1024x314.png" alt="" width="655" height="201" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/lpm-team-1024x314.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/lpm-team-300x92.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/lpm-team-768x235.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/lpm-team-1536x470.png 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/lpm-team.png 1652w" sizes="(max-width: 655px) 100vw, 655px" /></p>
<p><strong>Louisville Public Media’s</strong> work with BizLab centered on integrating their new digital property, Do502, into their existing network of stations and membership offerings. Do502.com is an event listing site with a focus on curated lists that help people find new things to do and new places to explore in Louisville, KY.</p>
<p>Louisville’s BizLab experiments focused on creating and curating events specifically for the Do502 audience. Early research in the project uncovered that Do502 readers crave limited-access engagements and exclusive series, and the team used their project to explore how to engage their audience in this way. The team also experimented with how to launch and promote a membership to Do502, distinct and separate from Louisville Public Media’s existing membership program.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2731  alignnone" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/wdet-team-1024x359.png" alt="" width="656" height="230" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/wdet-team-1024x359.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/wdet-team-300x105.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/wdet-team-768x269.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/wdet-team-1536x538.png 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/wdet-team.png 1718w" sizes="(max-width: 656px) 100vw, 656px" /></p>
<p><strong>WDET</strong>, Detroit’s NPR Station, has identified many local, small businesses who are aligned with the station’s values, but can’t afford typical radio underwriting pricing. Additionally, it is neither efficient nor profitable for a WDET underwriting representative to pursue sponsorship at the level of a small business budget.</p>
<p>WDET worked with BizLab exploring social media underwriting opportunities for small businesses. Through in-person interviews, WDET discovered that small businesses frequently use Facebook and Instagram to promote events and drive traffic. They also learned these businesses care about the local community, telling their unique story and providing a niche service and product. They love WDET’s non-profit mission and its reputation within the local community. With this information, the team tested a WDET-branded social media post product on Facebook and Instagram that affiliated the small business with the WDET brand and halo, reaching a network of potential consumers. By prototyping it as an online, semi-automated process to sell and produce, WDET created an affordable underwriting product.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2730 alignnone" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/capradio-team-1024x416.png" alt="" width="474" height="193" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/capradio-team-1024x416.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/capradio-team-300x122.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/capradio-team-768x312.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/capradio-team.png 1232w" sizes="(max-width: 474px) 100vw, 474px" /></p>
<p><strong>Capital Public Radio,</strong> in Sacramento, CA, has an existing network of NPR stations across California where in exchange for Capital Public Radio’s State Capitol reporting, partner stations provide weekly underwriting units on their airwaves. The BizLab project was focused on re-designing the function and mission of this network, Capital Public Radio Network (CPRN).</p>
<p>CPRN enjoyed financial success in its early years, through selling these partner station underwriting units, but revenue began to decline in 2009 and eventually fell to zero. Through BizLab, the team explored how to resurrect, restructure, and return CPRN to financial sustainability, by redefining the product in terms of the value it offered to underwriters: a one-stop-shop for reaching NPR listeners across the state of California.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2729  alignnone" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/wlrn-team-1024x312.png" alt="" width="655" height="200" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/wlrn-team-1024x312.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/wlrn-team-300x92.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/wlrn-team-768x234.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/wlrn-team-1536x469.png 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/wlrn-team.png 1626w" sizes="(max-width: 655px) 100vw, 655px" /></p>
<p><strong>WLRN</strong> in Miami has invested in their local coverage of the environment and climate change with a commitment to hosting local events and hiring an environment reporter. WLRN’s goal in their BizLab project was to explore how to generate revenue through this topical coverage and the creation of an environmental newsletter.</p>
<p>Their BizLab experiments tested different newsletter content, styles, and format, and then expanded into a technology integration project: the team brought in News Revenue Hub to integrate their newsletter, payment and CRM platforms. The final environmental newsletter product combines journalism and community engagement through the delivery of specialized content on a significant community issue. The newsletter is driving new membership, increasing current levels of giving, and is a vehicle for targeting specific underwriters for this newly developed product.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2728  alignnone" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/vpr-team-1024x332.png" alt="" width="654" height="212" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/vpr-team-1024x332.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/vpr-team-300x97.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/vpr-team-768x249.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/vpr-team-1536x498.png 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/vpr-team.png 1678w" sizes="(max-width: 654px) 100vw, 654px" /></p>
<p>Vermont Public Radio’s vision is “exploring the whole Vermont story, together” – no small task when you consider VPR is a statewide public radio service in a rural state with few concentrated population centers. In 2018, during VPR’s 14-county listening tour, listeners consistently asked for more coverage of their local communities. VPR’s BizLab project centered around the idea of making the station “feel more local” in Windham County, located in Southern VT, to determine if this would increase loyalty, engagement, and ultimately, revenue.</p>
<p>To accomplish this, in partnership with VPR’s dedicated Southern Vermont reporter, the team worked to raise the visibility of regional content and the reporter’s profile in the community via social media and a new email newsletter. They also increased engagement with the community by soliciting story ideas and planning a “News &amp; Brews” event to involve residents in the news gathering process. They are now also exploring the possibility of geo-targeted underwriting opportunities that would allow local businesses to reach their local customers.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Summit Panel: Editorial and Business Working Together</title>
		<link>/2020/01/summit-panel-recap-editorial-and-business-working-together/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joan DiMicco]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 22:19:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2019 Summit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News from the Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WDET]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WLRN]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2489</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For all media organizations, striking the balance between the desire to diversify revenue streams and the need to maintain high standards of editorial integrity is an urgent concern. In this panel, we will discuss how three of BizLab stations successfully navigated a sustained collaboration between editorial and business-oriented teams at their organizations.  Panel Video Moderator: [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For all media organizations, striking the balance between the desire to diversify revenue streams and the need to maintain high standards of editorial integrity is an urgent concern. In this panel, we will discuss how three of BizLab stations successfully navigated a sustained collaboration between editorial and business-oriented teams at their organizations. </span></p>
<h2>Panel Video</h2>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Editorial and Business Working Together in Public Radio (2019 BizLab Summit)" width="580" height="326" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wMknsJMCuGA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><b>Moderator:</b></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.wbur.org/inside/staff/adrian-ma">Adrian Ma</a>, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bostonomix </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Reporter, WBUR</span></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Panelists: </b></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/brendankinney/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Brendan Kinney</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Senior Vice President for Marketing and Development, Vermont Public Radio</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/giselle-reid-09935a119/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Giselle Reid</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Director of Strategic Initiatives, Friends of WLRN</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/meta-stange-0a15a064/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meta Stange</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Digital Producer, WDET</span></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Side-Panel: </b></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.vpr.org/people/howard-weiss-tisman"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Howard Weiss-Tisman</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Reporter for Southern Vermont &amp; The Connecticut River Valley, Vermont Public Radio</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.wlrn.org/people/katie-lepri"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Katie Lepri</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Engagement Producer, WLRN</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://wdet.org/author/199/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Toby Tabaczynski</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Associate Director, Business Development &amp; Marketing, WDET</span></li>
</ul>
<h2>Audience Questions</h2>
<p><em>[The panelists provided written answers to audience questions not covered in the live discussion.]</em></p>
<h4><b>Did you find opportunities to better serve your audience by collaborating together?</b></h4>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Meta (WDET):</strong> Absolutely. Editorial/business collaboration allows us to present a more cohesive product to our audience, both on-air and online.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Howard (VPR): </strong>Yes. Our project opened a direct link with some listeners. I think they felt closer to the station in communicating through our newsletters. </span></li>
</ul>
<h4><b>What are ways you fostered communication between your business &amp; editorial folks? Cross-departmental team meetings, Slack channels, email groups—what worked?</b></h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Meta (WDET):</strong> We’ve found that periodic cross-team meetings are effective for fostering communication across the station and breaking down silos. For our station, the ability to connect in-person reduces miscommunication and enhances understanding of what everyone is working on. We have bi-monthly membership meetings and a monthly marketing meeting, both of which have representatives from membership, marketing, underwriting, and editorial. Also, the business team is always welcome to pop in to our morning news meetings to keep a finger on the pulse of what’s going on editorially, and they often do stop by!</li>
<li><strong>Toby (WDET):</strong> Adding on to what Meta said, the ability to work together comes from building respect and trust which is what we do at WDET.  If you have that, conversations and mutual commitment can take place. We are fortunate at WDET that we have those relationships.</li>
<li><strong>Howard (VPR):</strong> Since I don’t work in the same office as the development team, we swap email messages regularly. I felt like I was always in the loop and knew what was going on. There were no surprises.</li>
<li><strong>Brendan (VPR):</strong> We formed a podcast committee a number of years ago that brought representatives from various departments together to coordinate our efforts. As a result, we have built the infrastructure necessary to sell and deliver sponsorships, hold events with impact around the state and promote the shows more effectively. We use in-person meetings, Slack channels and email to communicate.</li>
</ul>
<h4><b>Is the concept of a firewall outdated? Should we be more concerned with transparency, disclosure and truth as opposed to separation and sequestration?</b></h4>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Toby (WDET):</strong> Yes. All departments can still protect their unique goals and mission AND have open conversations to explore areas to work together and compromise as needed. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Howard (VPR):</strong> We have to stop using the word “Firewall” when talking about BizLab projects. Firewalls are real. They are important and they should not be penetrated. A development project can never direct content. Ever. The reason I think it is so damaging to continue using the word is because I don’t think these projects have anything to do with firewalls and continuing to use the word will scare away people who might have some legitimate issues with this. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Brendan (VPR):</strong> The firewall plays an important role in ensuring integrity in our editorial process. However, organizations can respect the firewall </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">and</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> better coordinate efforts to make our organizations sustainable for the long term. </span></li>
</ul>
<h4><b>Is “engagement” on the revenue side or the content side? Some of the comments seem to imply that focusing on engagement is bad for journalism.</b></h4>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Meta (WDET):</strong> For us, it’s both. We rely on community-first reporting for a significant number of stories which requires engagement to be at the forefront of our editorial process. What we’ve found through that process is that our content is more thorough and representative of the communities that we are reporting on. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Katie (WLRN):</strong> For us at WLRN, it’s both, too. Although, when I talk about engagement, I’m strictly speaking about editorial. Stories about the economy, immigration, healthcare, education, etc. are told through the lens of the experiences of people who reside in our communities. The community is a big part of our newsroom. </span></li>
</ul>
<h4><b>Why is it an either/or? Why can’t engagement be on both revenue and content? </b></h4>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Brendan (VPR):</strong> Engagement has largely been the purview of development at VPR. Over the last few years our thinking &#8211; and practice &#8211; has evolved thanks to two initiatives: the first was the launch of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Brave Little State</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a “people-powered” show that uses Hearken to engage the audience in helping choose topics; the second was a 2018 statewide listening tour that brought us to all 14 counties in Vermont to learn how we could better serve our audience (and to help our new CEO learn about his new home state). </span></li>
</ul>
<h4><b>How do you balance the need to set editorial priorities early enough to raise money, while keeping flexibility to respond to changing news events?</b></h4>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Howard (VPR):</strong> From the start my development people said, &#8220;Just continue doing what you do and we will find ways to get your stories to the audience.&#8221; So they never directed my reporting to raise money. </span></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Is having reporters &#8220;pitch&#8221; on air in a pledge drive considered &#8220;okay&#8221; or &#8220;not good&#8221;?</b></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Meta (WDET):</strong> Our pledge drives are an all hands on deck process. Everyone gets on air at some point, and our listeners seem to appreciate hearing directly from the reporters, hosts, and producers that they already hear from every day. </span></li>
</ul>
<h4><b>Have any of your content people made a suggestion on how to word a donation ask?</b></h4>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Katie (WLRN):</strong> As far as I know, no.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Howard (VPR):</strong> No </span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Brendan (VPR):</strong> As I mentioned during the panel, many of our news staff “pitch” during membership drives and craft an ask on the air. They have the opportunity to word their own asks. </span></li>
</ul>
<h4><b>From a pledge perspective, do you consider a reporter issuing CTAs a firewall breach, such as giving phone # and web address?</b></h4>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Meta (WDET):</strong> Without member support, there is no reporting. Our news team is keenly aware of this and willing to make direct asks during pledge drives.</span></li>
</ul>
<h4><b>I’m getting the sense that newsletters seem to be controlled by the business side of the house. Is this the case? Why?</b></h4>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Howard (VPR): </strong>For me this whole project has come out of business. So when they say they want to send a newsletter or link a story on Facebook I’m happy to do what I can to make it happen. With my workload I am more than happy for business to lead it, though there was some back-and-forth when we were deciding how to word some emails. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Brendan (VPR):</strong> We have worked collaboratively to develop newsletters at VPR. We have a daily “headlines” newsletter that is curated by our </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Morning Edition </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">producer. We also launched a newsletter for our BizLab project which automatically ships whenever a new story is posted to our website about Southern Vermont. Our development team worked with our digital team to develop the template and the technical capability to have it go out with minimal intervention. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Meta (WDET):</strong> At WDET, our newsletters are editorial products, but we work with marketing + underwriting to determine if there are additional opportunities for support/sponsorship. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Katie (WLRN):</strong> At WLRN, we currently have a “member” newsletter that’s controlled by Friends of WLRN. But our BizLab project opened the door for our first newsroom-written newsletter. We’ve since launched another from the newsroom and a third will be coming in 2020. </span></li>
</ul>
<h4><b>For WLRN &#8211; has your relationship with the other side changed at all as a result of your project? </b></h4>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Katie (WLRN): </strong>Yes, definitely. It’s more open than it used to be. Before this project, I could bet that business didn’t know what was happening in editorial and vice versa. That’s changed. Employees from Friends of WLRN frequent editorial’s weekly story meetings. And they will definitely be more collaboration in the future. </span></li>
</ul>
<h4><b>How important is it for development/business staff to be regular consumers of the content your station is making? Should it be required?</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></h4>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Meta (WDET): </strong>Our business/development staff is constantly consuming the content that the editorial team creates, which makes it much easier to work collaboratively and nimbly because the business team already has a baseline understanding of what we’re working on. I guess the bigger question is if the business staff isn’t interested in consuming your station’s editorial content, why would they want to sell it? </span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Brendan (VPR):</strong> Much of our “case for support” is about the work of our content team, so our expectation is that staff are also listeners and readers of our content. I would consider it a big red flag if you have to “require” staff to consume your station’s content! </span></li>
</ul>
<h4><b>At most entrepreneurial news startups, editorial and business sides are working closely together on new initiatives. Is public radio handicapping itself?</b></h4>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Toby (WDET):</strong> There are certainly some legacy habits and structures that exist in public radio and for that matter, have existed in all traditional media.  Other media have been making changes for years. Public radio has a unique opportunity to change this now. </span></li>
</ul>
<h4><b>Not necessarily a firewall breach, but ALL content people have to be aware that they ARE revenue generators. I know many who *aggressively* don&#8217;t get that. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f641.png" alt="🙁" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></b></h4>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Toby (WDET):</strong> If everyone understands they can help and have a connection to helping generate revenue, mind sets are changed and doors open.  Often, people feel they need to “stay in their lane” and not look at the bigger picture of how they can help. Some of the best revenue ideas we have have come from staff outside of the Underwriting team. </span></li>
</ul>
<h4>Thanks, everyone!</h4>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Your Time of Day Traffic Patterns Reveal About Your Site</title>
		<link>/2020/01/what-your-time-of-day-traffic-patterns-reveal-about-your-site/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ted Fuller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 20:26:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[BizLab Experiments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LPM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WAMU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WBUR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WDET]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WLRN]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2554</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As an analytics professional, part of what attracted me to the work of WBUR’s BizLab for the opportunity to compare analytics across a variety of sites from around the country, each with differing user-bases, use-cases and key features. As we began research efforts with our cohort stations early this year, I reviewed each partner organization&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As an analytics professional, part of what attracted me to the work of WBUR’s BizLab for the opportunity to compare analytics across a variety of sites from around the country, each with differing user-bases, use-cases and key features.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As we began research efforts with our cohort stations early this year, I reviewed each partner organization&#8217;s analytics data and immediately began to notice distinctive patterns in the time of day when users engaged with each site. BizLab cohort partners included a local event-focused site and a hip local news site, as well as the regional public radio news sites you may be most familiar with. It’s important to keep these divergent content profiles in mind when comparing traffic between sites.</span></p>
<p>Our first two cohort partners managed sites which illustrated the distinctive traffic patterns yielded by two very different types of content. Do502 is an events site offering a guide to shows, food and activities in Louisville and DCist is a news site with an informal tone which offers stories that matter to people who live and/or work in Washington DC.</p>
<p>While DCist sees peaks of mobile traffic during each commute and steady desktop traffic during the workday, Do502 desktop traffic hits its peaks on Monday and Fridays when their events emails are sent out. Also, Do502 mobile activity reaches its peak on Fridays and Saturdays, while DCist mobile activity falls off on the weekends. This is when most events covered by Do502 occur, and meanwhile DCist readers know not to expect to see new content published on weekends.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Sparklines-DCist-and-Do502.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2555 size-full aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Sparklines-DCist-and-Do502.png" alt="Time of Day Traffic Patterns" width="974" height="504" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Sparklines-DCist-and-Do502.png 974w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Sparklines-DCist-and-Do502-300x155.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Sparklines-DCist-and-Do502-768x397.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 974px) 100vw, 974px" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With that in mind, I identified a few common time-of-day patterns in our cohort analytics data; have a look, then use the final section to compare your own data.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">If: Your traffic sees mid-day plateaus during the work-week:</span></h2>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Then: You provide a steady feed of diverting content which draws your users during their workday.</span></h2>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Devils-Tower-Pattern.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2575 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Devils-Tower-Pattern.png" alt="" width="600" height="371" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Devils-Tower-Pattern.png 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Devils-Tower-Pattern-300x186.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a></p>
<figure id="attachment_2573" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2573" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/dreyfus.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2573 size-medium" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/dreyfus-300x270.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="270" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/dreyfus-300x270.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/dreyfus.jpg 470w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2573" class="wp-caption-text">This is important! This means something!</figcaption></figure>
<ul>
<li>Consider this context as you make editorial decisions, or as you decide how to interpret analytics results.</li>
<li>Google Analytics is not revealing communiqués from Spielbergian extraterrestrials. When your plateau is distinct as it is in the example, it’s likely that you have a localized audience.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/The-farther-from-DC-the-smoother-the-traffic-pattern-1.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2561 size-full aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/The-farther-from-DC-the-smoother-the-traffic-pattern-1.png" alt="" width="600" height="371" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/The-farther-from-DC-the-smoother-the-traffic-pattern-1.png 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/The-farther-from-DC-the-smoother-the-traffic-pattern-1-300x186.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/WBUR-Exhibits-the-Same-Pattern-03.png"><img loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2558 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/WBUR-Exhibits-the-Same-Pattern-03.png" alt="" width="600" height="371" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/WBUR-Exhibits-the-Same-Pattern-03.png 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/WBUR-Exhibits-the-Same-Pattern-03-300x186.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">If: Your traffic features distinct peaks:</span></h2>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Then: Your users are largely choosing to engage with your property at the beginning and close of each day.</span></h2>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Cat-Ears-Pattern-1.png"><img loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2560 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Cat-Ears-Pattern-1.png" alt="" width="600" height="371" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Cat-Ears-Pattern-1.png 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Cat-Ears-Pattern-1-300x186.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">It might be worthwhile to review sessions per user per day to understand whether for your site this pattern indicates that users are coming twice each day, or that there are two cohorts of users who respectively visit in the morning and evening.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">To understand what your users are doing during peaks, identify your peak hours and then see what sources of acquisition are strongest during peaks compared to the rest of the day.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This pattern could indicate that your site’s engagement is driven by the commute, especially if it’s especially pronounced for your mobile users.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">If: Your weekday traffic exhibits a sharp morning incline, then a slow decline for the rest of the day:</span></h2>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Then: Your audience has good reason to check in with you first thing, but you aren’t providing as compelling a reason to return later in the day.</span><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Whale-Pattern.png"><img loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2562 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Whale-Pattern.png" alt="" width="600" height="371" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Whale-Pattern.png 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Whale-Pattern-300x186.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you see this pattern in your site, consider whether it&#8217;s a strategic priority to attract more users throughout the afternoon. If so:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Consider regularly publishing some content in the afternoon, so your users can have a reason to return after their morning session.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re sending newsletters in the mornings, check to see how much newsletter traffic is responsible for your morning peak. If its effect is negligible, consider some A/B tests around sending the newsletter in the afternoons instead.</span></li>
</ul>
<h2><b>Now you try!</b></h2>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Start by adding this report: </span><a href="https://analytics.google.com/analytics/web/template?uid=TtIV35NvQaG2IRNCKFKARA"><b>SessionData Extract|v01</b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to the Google Analytics instance for the property you’d like to measure. <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Import-Custom-report.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2564 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Import-Custom-report.png" alt="" width="755" height="330" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Import-Custom-report.png 755w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Import-Custom-report-300x131.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 755px) 100vw, 755px" /></a></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Set a recent date-range which results in no more than 5,000 rows of data in the report; that should give you plenty of space to extract a full year’s worth of data.<a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/set-date-range-in-custom-report.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2565 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/set-date-range-in-custom-report.png" alt="" width="861" height="461" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/set-date-range-in-custom-report.png 861w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/set-date-range-in-custom-report-300x161.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/set-date-range-in-custom-report-768x411.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 861px) 100vw, 861px" /></a></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Set the report to show the maximum 5,000 rows, then export this report to google sheets.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Open this template google sheet I’ve built. The template is view-only so <strong>make a copy for yourself </strong>so you can edit. </span><a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1dS09d_ajIUdh-R501eJ0gZCh-FiYOpVCwbiBNaXfEWA/edit?usp=sharing"><span style="font-weight: 400;">TEMPLATE &#8211; Time of Day Comparison</span></a><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/template-screenshot.png"><img loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2566 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/template-screenshot.png" alt="" width="989" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/template-screenshot.png 989w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/template-screenshot-300x91.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/template-screenshot-768x233.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 989px) 100vw, 989px" /></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now, copy the data from your exported google analytics report into the <strong>TABLE tab</strong> of your copy of the google sheet. The charts on the subsequent tabs will populate with the data you’ve added. Which of the described patterns or BizLab cohort station patterns does your traffic most closely resemble? Take a screenshot and tweet me your results at <a href="https://twitter.com/ted_fuller">@Ted_Fuller</a>!</span></li>
</ol>
<p><b>Advanced:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Apply custom segments to the SessionData Extract report to extract data for specific segments, i.e. regions, activities, demographics etc. Then, compare the data you’ve collected!</span></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Small-Multiples-Map-Weekday.png"><img loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2567 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Small-Multiples-Map-Weekday.png" alt="" width="960" height="540" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Small-Multiples-Map-Weekday.png 960w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Small-Multiples-Map-Weekday-300x169.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Small-Multiples-Map-Weekday-768x432.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a> <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Small-Multiples-Map-Weekend.png"><img loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2568 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Small-Multiples-Map-Weekend.png" alt="" width="960" height="540" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Small-Multiples-Map-Weekend.png 960w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Small-Multiples-Map-Weekend-300x169.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Small-Multiples-Map-Weekend-768x432.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a></p>
<p>I&#8217;d like to thank Amira Valliani of <a href="https://www.glow.fm/">glow.fm</a> and Joan DiMicco of the <a href="/">WBUR Bizlab</a> for inspiring this article.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Summit Panel: Text Messaging and Public Radio Donations</title>
		<link>/2020/01/summit-panel-text-messaging-and-public-radio-donations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joan DiMicco]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 20:25:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2019 Summit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News from the Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GiveLively]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GroundSource]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hustle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[KALW]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WBUR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WLRN]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2706</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are more technologies than ever that are specifically designed to make the donation and engagement process more streamlined for listeners. In this panel, three stations that have effectively integrated text messaging tools into their existing donor strategies will discuss best practices in different contexts. Moderator: Joan DiMicco, Executive Director, BizLab, WBUR Panelists: Tina Pamintuan, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There are more technologies than ever that are specifically designed to make the donation and engagement process more streamlined for listeners. In this panel, three stations that have effectively integrated text messaging tools into their existing donor strategies will discuss best practices in different contexts.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Text Messaging and Public Radio Donations (2019 BizLab Summit)" width="580" height="326" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gNJL4AWm324?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><strong>Moderator: </strong></p>
<p>Joan DiMicco, Executive Director, BizLab, WBUR</p>
<p><strong>Panelists: </strong></p>
<p>Tina Pamintuan, General Manager, KALW, using <a href="https://www.givelively.org/">Give Lively</a> for donations</p>
<p>Katie Lepri, Engagement Producer, WLRN, using <a href="https://www.groundsource.co/">GroundSource</a> for audience engagement</p>
<p>Kathleen Moura, Membership Manager, WBUR, using <a href="https://www.hustle.com/">Hustle</a> for donor engagement</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Summit: Full Day Live Stream</title>
		<link>/2019/12/summit-full-day-live-stream/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joan DiMicco]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 21:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2019 Summit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News from the Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BizLab Methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CapRadio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GiveLively]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[glow.fm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GroundSource]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hustle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[KALW]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[KUOW]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LPM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NHPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PRX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WAMU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WBUR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WDET]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WLRN]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2716</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On December 10, 2019, over 100 individuals from media organizations, including many NPR stations, convened for a day of learning. The Summit was a fast-paced day of lightning talks and panel discussions, with invited speakers and station innovators sharing their stations’ new paths to sustainability. We shared best practices, tools, tips, and real life examples [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On December 10, 2019, over 100 individuals from media organizations, including many NPR stations, convened for a day of learning. The Summit was a fast-paced day of lightning talks and panel discussions, with invited speakers and station innovators sharing their stations’ new paths to sustainability.</p>
<p>We shared best practices, tools, tips, and real life examples of this work, enabling attendees to hit the ground running at their own media organizations. The Summit covered revenue generation through digital audience engagement, spinning off new brands, event monetization, text-to-donate platforms, and podcast donation strategies.</p>
<p>https://youtu.be/dIqNF0-vSXg</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>November 2019 Webinar: Aligning Content Plans With Revenue Goals</title>
		<link>/2019/10/november-2019-webinar-aligning-content-plans-with-revenue-goals/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lindsy Goldberg]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 15:54:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Webinars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WDET]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WLRN]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2384</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To maintain journalistic integrity, most public radio stations have rigid boundaries between newsrooms and fundraising departments. The public media Code of Integrity states that media organizations will: Protect the editorial process from the fact and appearance of undue influence, exercising care in seeking and accepting funds and setting careful boundaries between contributors and content creators. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To maintain journalistic integrity, most public radio stations have rigid boundaries between newsrooms and fundraising departments. The public media </span><a href="http://www.codeofintegrity.org/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Code of Integrity</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> states that media organizations will: </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Protect the editorial process from the fact and appearance of undue influence, exercising care in seeking and accepting funds and setting careful boundaries between contributors and content creators. </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">In BizLab’s work with our cohort stations this year, we have invested a great deal of time in helping stations navigate these boundaries while acknowledging the importance of diversifying revenue streams in the digital age. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Three of BizLab’s cohort stations have practical experience in navigating these boundaries as they implemented their revenue generation idea. All three found ways to successfully collaborate and leverage shared goals to the benefit of the station. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Join us on November 12th to hear a panel discussion, with question and discussion time at the end. BizLab’s Experience Strategist, Sarah Bloomer, will facilitate. </span></p>
<h2>Date</h2>
<p>Tuesday, November 12, 2019, 3-4pm Eastern Time</p>
<h2>Speakers</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em>Meta Stange</em>, Digital Producer for WDET, also runs the station’s social channels and creates digital editorial content for wdet.org. Meta will talk about using social media to enable small businesses in Detroit to reach the WDET audience while staying within station guidelines and remaining true to their brand., . </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em>Brendan Kinney</em>, Senior Vice President for Marketing and Development at Vermont Public Radio, will share how they are working with their  journalist who covers the region of southern Vermont, giving him greater exposure and connection to the local community. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em>Giselle Reid</em>, Director of Strategic Initiatives at Friends of WLRN in Miami, will share how they have built a strong partnership with the digital programming team to produce an online newsletter focused on environmental news.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://zoom.us/meeting/register/8a328ac7dd4d1f9966858a512be5123a"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-1022 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Screen-Shot-2018-09-10-at-4.16.06-PM.png" alt="" width="262" height="106" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>July 2019 Webinar: Transactional Business Models in Nonprofit Media</title>
		<link>/2019/06/july-2019-webinar-transactional-business-models-in-nonprofit-media/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lindsy Goldberg]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 17:31:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Webinars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Affiliate Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Selling Tickets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VTDigger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WBUR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WLRN]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1750</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Is your nonprofit news organization reliant on donations and underwriting? BizLab&#8217;s July webinar presents three alternative ways of generating revenue at nonprofit news organizations: The VTDigger (http://vtdigger.org),/ as a service to Vermont businesses, post press releases from businesses, state agencies, political organizations and nonprofits.  They have been expanding the services connected with press releases to explore if [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<div>
<p>Is your nonprofit news organization reliant on donations and underwriting? BizLab&#8217;s July webinar presents three alternative ways of generating revenue at nonprofit news organizations:</p>
<p><strong>The VTDigger</strong> (<a href="http://vtdigger.org/">http://vtdigger.org/</a>), as a service to Vermont businesses, <strong>post press releases from businesses, state agencies, political organizations and nonprofits.</strong>  They have been expanding the services connected with press releases to explore if there are revenue opportunities for VTDigger. During the webinar, <strong>Founder and Editor Anne Galloway</strong> will share results from this experiment.</p>
<p><strong>WLRN&#8217;s Cultural Connection</strong> (<a href="https://www.culturalconnection.org/">https://www.culturalconnection.org/</a>) is a long running service provided to South Florida, connecting theatre venues with customer&#8217;s looking for <strong>last-minute ticket discounts</strong>. And this primarily digital service generates significant revenue for WLRN. <strong>Brendan Glynn, Director of Corporate Underwriting at Friends of WLRN, Inc.</strong>, will share the history of how this service was established and how the station manages the business.</p>
<p><strong>WBUR&#8217;s BizLab</strong> is exploring <strong>affiliate marketing</strong> as a revenue source for the station. With outside contributors writing product recommendation &#8220;guides,&#8221; WBUR launched a site called WBUR Guides (<a href="http://guides.wbur.org/">http://guides.wbur.org/</a>) that highlights interesting products on the market geared for the public radio audience. By testing and iterating, we are learning what works in terms of topics, products, distribution, and promotion. <strong>Matt Aufiero, BizLab 2019 Fellow,</strong> will share results.</p>
</div>
</div>
<h2>Date</h2>
<p>Tuesday, July 23, 2019, 3-4pm EDT</p>
<h2>Speakers</h2>
<ul>
<li>Matt Aufiero, WBUR BizLab</li>
<li>Brendan Glynn, WLRN</li>
<li>Anne Galloway, VTDigger</li>
</ul>
<h2>Recording</h2>
<p><a href="http://https://youtu.be/tEyQMSo-AXo">http://https://youtu.be/tEyQMSo-AXo</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
