<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Sarah Barden &#8211; Public Radio Biz Lab</title>
	<atom:link href="/author/sbardenbu-edu/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 14:41:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/cropped-bizlab_round_wordmark_yellow-1-32x32.gif</url>
	<title>Sarah Barden &#8211; Public Radio Biz Lab</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>New Revenue From Event Donations &#038; Ticket Sales</title>
		<link>/2019/10/new-revenue-from-event-donations-ticket-sales/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Barden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 03:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[BizLab Experiments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BizLab Fellows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Selling Tickets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WBUR]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2353</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is the third post of a three part series about BizLab’s work with WBUR CitySpace. This post discusses two donation experiments and modeling of ticket sales revenue. If your station hosts events and has been unsure about how to ask for donations and approach ticket pricing, this post is for you! [I’m Sarah Barden, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is the third post of a <a href="/2019/08/identifying-revenue-potential-for-events-at-wbur-cityspace/">three part series about BizLab’s work with WBUR CitySpace</a>. This post discusses two donation experiments and modeling of ticket sales revenue. If your station hosts events and has been unsure about how to ask for donations and approach ticket pricing, this post is for you!</span></p>
<blockquote><p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">[I’m Sarah Barden, a BizLab Summer Fellow investigating revenue streams for WBUR CitySpace. I just graduated from a dual degree program between</span></i><a href="https://www.wellesley.edu/"> <i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wellesley College</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and</span></i><a href="http://www.olin.edu/"> <i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Olin College</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> studying mathematics, engineering, and user experience design, and I&#8217;ve started a Master’s in</span></i><a href="https://mem.dartmouth.edu/"> <i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Engineering Management at Dartmouth</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> this fall.]</span></i></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Two main ways to generate revenue from your audience at events are through tickets sales and donations. Making revenue through tickets sales has been CitySpace’s main source of audience revenue so far, with about $58,000 in net ticket revenue for events since opening in February, through the end of July. </span></p>
<h3><b>Asking for Donation at Events</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Prior to this summer, CitySpace had not asked event attendees for donations. Based on our data analysis, that over 70% of our attendees are not WBUR donors, yet the majority of event attendees are WBUR listeners and familiar with WBUR&#8217;s events and content. </span></p>
<p>Because of this, we hypothesized this audience was primed to give to WBUR&#8217;s CitySpace.  So we decided to test asking for donations both at the event and at the moment of ticket purchase. <span style="font-weight: 400;">For our testing, we used two different platforms: </span><a href="https://www.givelively.org/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">GiveLively,</span></a> a donation platform, <span style="font-weight: 400;">and </span><a href="https://www.ovationtix.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">OvationTix</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, our existing ticketing system. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We first used </span><a href="https://www.givelively.org/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">GiveLively</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to test live donations asks during events at CitySpace. The GiveLively fundraising platform is free for nonprofits that includes text-to-initiate donations and a live display showing real-time donations. During events, we could project a screen with instructions on how to donate: </span><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/givelivelyonscreen.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2357" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/givelivelyonscreen-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="262" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/givelivelyonscreen-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/givelivelyonscreen-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/givelivelyonscreen-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/givelivelyonscreen.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 350px) 100vw, 350px" /></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/givelively.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2358 alignright" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/givelively-498x1024.jpg" alt="" width="286" height="588" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/givelively-498x1024.jpg 498w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/givelively-146x300.jpg 146w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/givelively-768x1579.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/givelively.jpg 778w" sizes="(max-width: 286px) 100vw, 286px" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When attendees text “cityspace” to the number 44-321, they receive a donation link where they can donate using Google/Apple Pay or credit/debit card. The mobile-friendly webpage is shown below:  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We made asks at three different events, receiving $216 in donations from 11 donors. There were 306 attendees total over these three events, so only 3.6% of attendees donated, and donated an average of $19.64 per donation. We had widely varied results across events: most of the 11 donations came from just one event, which we suspect has to do with the emotional content of the event, inspiring people to donate. </span></p>
<h3><b>Asking for Donations at Ticket Purchase</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After the event donation experiments, we turned on the ability for people to donate to WBUR CitySpace while purchasing or reserving tickets through our ticketing system, </span><a href="https://www.ovationtix.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">OvationTix</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the first two weeks this capability was on, we received $167 from 27 donors. There were 585 ticket transactions total, so 4.6% of ticket buyers added a donation &#8212; a higher percentage than asking for donations with GiveLively at events.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There was an average of $6.19 per donation, which was significantly less than the average donation through GiveLively. This is likely due to the recommended donation amounts displayed. As seen in the screenshots below, the OvationTix preset amounts were 5, 10, 25, and 50, whereas in the GiveLively test, the presets were 10, 25, 50, and 100. </span></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ovationtix2.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2356" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ovationtix2-1024x504.png" alt="" width="598" height="294" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ovationtix2-1024x504.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ovationtix2-300x148.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ovationtix2-768x378.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ovationtix2.png 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 598px) 100vw, 598px" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Our experiments found that the effort to raise donations at events was high (because of our team needing to break the event flow and coach people on texting to donate) and the yield was lower than the zero effort approach of asking ticket purchasers for donations. Our team will continue to run experiments, including one where OvationTix is set to the same preset amounts as GiveLively, to compare more easily. But our overall conclusion is that donations are best asked at the time of ticket purchase. </span></p>
<h3><b>Ticket Pricing</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ticket sales were an existing revenue stream for CitySpace, and we wanted to analyze ways in which this revenue could be increased. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since opening, most events at CitySpace were priced between $0 to $20. We hosted 17 free events, 5 $5 events, 17 $10 events, 12 $15 events, 7 $20 events, and 1 $50 event. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the survey discussed in <a href="/2019/10/surveying-your-audience-to-identify-revenue-opportunities/">my prior post</a>, we found that price was not a driving factor in attending (which indicates price flexibility) and we received comments about pricing such as “</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Very reasonably priced which makes it affordable for a broader audience than many other events.” ($20 show) and “Thank you for making this affordable for the whole family.” ($20 show). </span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This led us to believe that we could raise prices for certain events, but how much and when? <strong>Our </strong></span><strong>CitySpace team wants to keep <i>some </i>low prices to have an economically, geographically, and racially diverse audience. Raising the price of all events to $50+ would make events economically out of reach for a desired population. But tickets can not always be free or below cost, because CitySpace needs to remain financially sustainable. </strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">More evidence for raising ticket prices is the relationship between ticket prices and attendance. In analyzing audience data, we found that that a lower ticket price is correlated with lower attendance. In the chart below, each of the vertical bars is one CitySpace event and the height of the bar is percent of ticket purchasers who attended. If 200 people bought tickets and 100 people came, the bar would be at 50% attendance. The data shows that as the price for events decreases, the percentage of attendees decreases. This relationship makes sense because the more you have financially invested in an event, the more likely it is that you will want to cash in on that investment by attending the event.  </span></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/graph-e1571106617416.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2360" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/graph-e1571106617416.png" alt="" width="660" height="355" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/graph-e1571106617416.png 990w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/graph-e1571106617416-300x161.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/graph-e1571106617416-768x413.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Because CitySpace wants to have some free and low cost tickets to not exclude any groups from attending, a mechanism for addressing the willingness of some to pay higher prices is variable pricing, which is offering different ticket prices for different levels of perks at an event. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Variable pricing is also a way to increase the number of attendees at an event. If tickets are $20, that might attract 100 people to the event. If there is also a discount ticket price for $10, it can attracts students, senior, or low-income individuals that otherwise would not have come. If there is also a high ticket price for $40 with better seats, for example, this attracts people who have more disposable income and perceive an added value for attending.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In analytical terms, a flat price of $20 might only make $2,000 in revenue, but with three different ticket prices, revenue increases to $3,000. The 100 people who bought regular tickets will still attend the event, but different ticket prices attract new buyers, as outlined in the table below:</span></p>
<table style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: center;"></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"><strong>Price</strong></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"><strong>Tickets Bought</strong></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"><strong>Price</strong></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"><strong>Tickets Bought</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: center;">Discounted Price</td>
<td style="text-align: center;"></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"></td>
<td style="text-align: center;">$10</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">20</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: center;">Regular Price</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">$20</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">100</td>
<td></td>
<td style="text-align: center;">$20</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">100</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: center;">Higher Price</td>
<td style="text-align: center;"></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"></td>
<td style="text-align: center;">$40</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">20</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: center;"><strong>Total Revenue</strong></td>
<td style="text-align: center;" colspan="2"><b>$2,000</b></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"></td>
<td style="text-align: center;" colspan="2"><b>$3,000</b></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To predict future ticket sales revenue based on variable pricing, you can use spreadsheet calculations to plan out how many events of each ticket price you plan to hold. For example, say you plan to aim for 60 events in a year and want half to be free or low cost. Predicting the tickets sold per event and how many of each event will show the total revenue for those events. You can add to this basic model premium and discount pricing, to fine tune the model to determine where variable pricing will most increase revenue. </span></p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Event type</strong></td>
<td><strong>Price of event</strong></td>
<td><strong>Number of events</strong></td>
<td><strong>Tickets sold per event</strong></td>
<td><strong>Revenue</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Free event</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">$0</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">10</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">100</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">$ &#8211;</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Low price event</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">$10</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">20</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">100</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">$ 20,000</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Standard event</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">$25</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">20</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">100</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">$ 50,000</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">High demand event</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">$50</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">10</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">100</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">$ 50,000</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Total</strong></td>
<td></td>
<td><strong>60</strong></td>
<td><strong>400</strong></td>
<td><b>$ 120,000</b></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The CitySpace team is currently testing variable pricing for events this fall, where higher ticket prices get front row seating and sometimes an extra gift, and they will be evaluating the revenue generated from these events.</span></p>
<h3><b>Summary</b></h3>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">For donations at events, we recommend choosing the ask strategy that works for you. <strong>In CitySpace’s case, using our ticketing platform to allow ticket purchasers to simply add on a donation was the best route forward,</strong> and doing live donation asks will only be done at a few events, since it is not feasible for the team to do live asks at all events. For events where your audience is seated for a long, unique event with breaks, like a conference, gala, or dinner, live asks may work very well.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Variable pricing is a wise move to increase revenue while keeping events affordable for certain populations.</strong> In particular, variable pricing can attract new attendees that would not have otherwise come. It is worth it to try this method at a few events to test out logistics, revenue amounts, and attendance.</span></li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Surveying Your Audience to Identify Revenue Opportunities</title>
		<link>/2019/10/surveying-your-audience-to-identify-revenue-opportunities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Barden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 02:07:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[BizLab Experiments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BizLab Fellows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WBUR]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2175</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is the second post of a three part series about BizLab’s work with WBUR CitySpace. This post is about the survey we used to collect feedback about events and understand audience motivations. If your station wants to start surveying your audiences at events or if you want to learn more about survey design, this [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is the </span><a href="https://wp.me/p7r6Jl-uG"><span style="font-weight: 400;">second post of a three part series</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> about BizLab’s work with WBUR CitySpace. This post is about the survey we used to collect feedback about events and understand audience motivations. If your station wants to start surveying your audiences at events or if you want to learn more about survey design, this post is for you! </span></p>
<blockquote><p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">[I’m Sarah Barden, a BizLab Summer Fellow investigating revenue streams for WBUR CitySpace. I just graduated from a dual degree program between</span></i><a href="https://www.wellesley.edu/"> <i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wellesley College</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and</span></i><a href="http://www.olin.edu/"> <i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Olin College</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> studying mathematics, engineering, and user experience design, and I&#8217;ve started a Master’s in</span></i><a href="https://mem.dartmouth.edu/"> <i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Engineering Management at Dartmouth</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> this fall.]</span></i></p></blockquote>
<h3><b><i>Goals of the Feedback Survey</i></b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Our learning goals for the survey were:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Get general feedback on events, both quantitative and qualitative</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Understand what brings people to events</span></li>
<li>Understand how people hear about our events</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Audience demographics</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This information reveal opportunities for new revenue. By combining these learnings with existing data about ticketing, attendance, and marketing efforts, we will be able to determine how our current pricing relates to value delivered. </span></p>
<h3><b><i>Survey Design</i></b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I used <a href="http://surveymonkey.com/">SurveyMonkey</a> to create a 14-question survey to be conducted after events in CitySpace and distributed through post-show emails. We collected 164 responses in total, from 9 events. The survey questions were:</span></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Which event did you attend at WBUR CitySpace?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overall, how well did the event meet your expectations?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">How would you rate the following aspects of the event? Speaker/Performer(s), Host/Moderator(s), Length of event, Facilities, Audience Q&amp;A, Concessions</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Would you recommend a WBUR CitySpace event to a friend? Why or why not?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">CitySpace is run by WBUR (Boston’s NPR News Station). Had you heard of WBUR before today?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">When deciding whether or not to attend this event, how important were the following? Topic, Speaker/Performer(s), Location at CitySpace, Date and Time, Price of Event.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">How did you hear about this event?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">How did you primarily get to this event?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">We are considering creating a CitySpace membership. What perks would you like to see in CitySpace events membership?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">What age range do you fall into?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Which of the following categories best describes you?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">What gender do you identify as?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Which race/ethnicity best describes you?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you would like to receive the WBUR CitySpace newsletter, please share your email here.</span></li>
</ol>
<h3><b><i>Response Collection In-Person vs. Email</i></b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Announcements were made at the beginning and end of the events asking people to complete the survey because this feedback would help us improve future events. After the event, we collected responses in the CitySpace lobby with one or two people asking attendees leaving the venue to fill out a short survey. We had one or two laptops, a tablet, or a link to fill out on a phone. The second collection method was a link to the survey in the post-show email, asking attendees to offer their feedback. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overall, we found that the in-person ask after the event generated more responses than the post-show email, but only if we were actively asking individuals for responses as they left and if we had enough devices to make the wait time as short as possible. The in-person ask was time and labor intensive, however, so if your team needs a simple survey solution, the post-show email ask can still bring in some responses.</span></p>
<h3><b><i>Significant Survey Results</i></b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overall, we had positive responses to our general feedback questions. 73% of survey respondents said the event they attended was “Better than expected” or “Much better than expected”, and each specific aspect (Speaker/Performer, Host/Moderator, Length of event, Facilities, Audience Q&amp;A, Concessions) was rated 4.4 or higher out of 5.0, except for Concessions, which was rated 3.8. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The following charts are some of the more surprising or significant results of the survey beyond general feedback.</span></p>
<h4><i>People attend CitySpace events for the topic, not the location or price.</i></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We asked “In deciding whether or not to attend this event, how important were the following?” and respondents rated each aspect on a 5-point scale “Extremely important, Very important, Somewhat important, Slightly important, Not at all important”.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The chart below shows that topic is the most influential factor for these survey respondents. Regardless of specific speakers, location, date/time, or price, <strong>people are coming for the topic of the event.</strong> The least important influences were location and price. </span><span style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">For location, people would be willing to see this event somewhere else, but we can not change the location of CitySpace. </span><span style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">Because the price was also rated low in importance, we now know that people would be willing to pay more for topics they love.</span></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Deciding-to-Attend.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2178 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Deciding-to-Attend-300x121.png" alt="" width="508" height="205" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Deciding-to-Attend-300x121.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Deciding-to-Attend-768x310.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Deciding-to-Attend-1024x413.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Deciding-to-Attend.png 1116w" sizes="(max-width: 508px) 100vw, 508px" /></a></p>
<h4><b><i>Most people come by car to CitySpace events</i></b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">We have heard anecdotally that transportation is a barrier to attending CitySpace events. </span></span><span style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">Driving a car in rush hour traffic and then finding parking near CitySpace can be difficult, but CitySpace is </span><span style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">about 50 feet from a public transit train stop in Boston. Given this, we were surprised that about 50% of attendees reported traveling by car to our events. This may be due to the timing of events in the evening: if most people are driving a car to work, attending a 6pm event likely means they drive directly from work. For those taking public transit, the commute could be up to an hour for those coming from outside the immediate area. To bring new audiences to CitySpace, beyond the neighboring areas, we are now considering offering Lyft or Uber codes, or similar, to support those interested in the event but unable to commute to the location.</span></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Getting-to-Events.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2180 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Getting-to-Events-300x131.png" alt="" width="529" height="231" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Getting-to-Events-300x131.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Getting-to-Events-768x335.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Getting-to-Events-1024x447.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Getting-to-Events.png 1136w" sizes="(max-width: 529px) 100vw, 529px" /></a></p>
<h4><b><i>People hear about CitySpace events in “Other” ways</i></b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We thought CitySpace&#8217;s email newsletter, website, and social media efforts were bringing in our audience. But almost 50% of survey respondents answered “Other” when responding to the question “How did you hear about this event?” This was very surprising to the CitySpace team! The free-form responses to “Other” mentioned friends, family and directly from the speakers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These responses are informing our marketing efforts. There may be ways to increase ticket sales through certain marketing channels, or use marketing efforts to offer discounts or special offers as ways to get more emails and more audience.</span></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Hearing-About-Events.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2181 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Hearing-About-Events-300x176.png" alt="" width="436" height="256" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Hearing-About-Events-300x176.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Hearing-About-Events.png 718w" sizes="(max-width: 436px) 100vw, 436px" /></a></p>
<h4><b><i>Most of the CitySpace audience are WBUR listeners, but not all are donors.</i></b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you read the first post in this series, I shared this data in learning about CitySpace’s audience. When asked “Had you heard of WBUR before today?” 42% said “Yes, I’m a member” and 46% said “Yes, I’m a listener but not a member.” A listener who is not a member (donor) is a potential donor. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We hope to convert these attendees into WBUR donors by offering more engaging programming, and inspiring them to donate.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The CitySpace team had thought attendees would be listeners, so were surprised that 12% of survey respondents were either not listeners or had not even heard of WBUR before attending an event.</span></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Listeners.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2183 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Listeners-300x266.png" alt="" width="369" height="327" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Listeners-300x266.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Listeners-768x681.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Listeners.png 918w" sizes="(max-width: 369px) 100vw, 369px" /></a></p>
<h3><b><i>Edit your survey to only collect useful data, but keep it similar!</i></b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After a successful run of the summer survey, we reviewed these results and decided to continue surveying our audience, but to make changes to the survey. We removed the questions that we felt we had found the answer to and adjusted questions we thought could be simplified. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We simplified some of the longer questions where respondents had to rate many aspects of the events on a relative scale. We also adjusted certain parts of the survey to be more specific, for example, the questions about ticket price. Overall, however, we kept the survey as similar as possible so that we could compare the results over time. </span></p>
<h3><b><i>Summary</i></b></h3>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In terms of what influences people to come to events, we found that the event&#8217;s topic on average was the most influential, followed by speaker/performer. In looking at specific events, such as a comedian or a podcast, speaker/performer outranks topic because the audience wanted to see that specific person. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since price was in the bottom two for important factors influencing attendees, we can infer that price is less important, and therefore people may be willing to pay more for people or topics they really want to hear. This matches up with some survey comments that mention CitySpace prices as being “reasonable.”</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Half of event attendees learn about CitySpace events outside of CitySpace’s direct outreach, instead through word of mouth, and other social media. The CitySpace team can use this insight to change their strategy on CitySpace social media marketing and also take advantage of these other forms of marketing in order to increase ticket sales and awareness.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">With so many listeners attending CitySpace events who are not yet donors, we believe this is a prime opportunity for donation asks at events, when buying tickets, or through email asks. The next post will dive more into how we tested asking for donations.</span></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overall, if your team has the ability to collect data through a post-event survey, think carefully about the questions you ask, and know that you can try the survey for a few weeks and then edit the questions as needed, though keeping it similar enough to compare results over time. This data on events not only helps improve general event structure, but with asking questions about people’s motivations for attending events and how they feel about price, you can gain insight into how flexible your audience is on prices and what they value most about the venue.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Identifying Revenue Potential For Events at WBUR CitySpace</title>
		<link>/2019/08/identifying-revenue-potential-for-events-at-wbur-cityspace/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Barden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 16:31:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[BizLab Experiments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BizLab Fellows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Selling Tickets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WBUR]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1902</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This post is the first of a three part series about BizLab’s work with WBUR CitySpace. WBUR CitySpace is WBUR’s state-of-the-art multimedia venue that opened in February 2019 hosting a wide array of events, such as live podcasts, stage performances, comedy events, screenings, and more. This summer we analyzed the revenue from previous events, surveyed [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This post is the first of a three part series about BizLab’s work with WBUR CitySpace. </span><a href="http://wbur.org/cityspace"><span style="font-weight: 400;">WBUR CitySpace</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is WBUR’s state-of-the-art multimedia venue that opened in February 2019 hosting a wide array of events, such as </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">live podcasts, stage performances, comedy events, screenings, and more. This summer we </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">analyzed the revenue from previous events, surveyed the audience, developed event pricing models, and tested donation asks at live events.</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">If your station hosts events, has an event space, or is considering hosting community events, this series is for you.</span></p>
<blockquote><p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">[I’m Sarah Barden, a BizLab Summer Fellow investigating revenue streams for WBUR CitySpace. I just graduated from a dual degree program between <a href="https://www.wellesley.edu/">Wellesley College</a> and <a href="http://www.olin.edu/">Olin College</a> studying mathematics, engineering, and user experience design, and I am starting a Master’s in </span></i><a href="https://mem.dartmouth.edu/"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Engineering Management at Dartmouth</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> this fall.]</span></i></p></blockquote>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-2004" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/post1image1-300x200.jpg" alt="Image of CitySpace." width="368" height="245" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/post1image1-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/post1image1-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/post1image1-1024x682.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/post1image1-930x620.jpg 930w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/post1image1.jpg 1700w" sizes="(max-width: 368px) 100vw, 368px" /></p>
<h3><b><i>What is WBUR CitySpace?</i></b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since opening five months ago, WBUR CitySpace has held 80+ events, including WBUR programming and partner programming with organizations like </span><a href="https://thewilbur.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Wilbur</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (a local, independently-owned venue focused on live comedy) and </span><a href="https://themoth.org/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Moth</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (a non-profit holding </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">theme-based storytelling events)</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The space can seat up to 270 people in a flexible space that includes an open lobby. Exterior glass walls invite curious pedestrians to watch the events and listen on the benches while live audio is streamed outside.</span></p>
<h3><b><i>Potential Revenue Ideas</i></b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When I arrived at the beginning of June, CitySpace had launched its events and the team was looking for insights into making more revenue. Ticket sales were currently the only audience revenue stream, so the team wanted to explore options beyond ticket sales. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I proposed several different areas for exploration this summer: asking for donations from the audience, adjusting ticket prices, membership options for CitySpace, and selling merchandise. </span></p>
<h3><em><b>Understanding the CitySpace audience</b></em></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">First, however, we needed to understand the CitySpace audience to help properly set up experiments. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The team had ticket buyer data available for events through our ticketing system, </span><a href="https://www.ovationtix.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">OvationTix</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (this data doesn’t include any partner events where they handle their own ticketing). </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I also created a survey to capture more data than the ticket sales from OvationTix. Some of the survey data is shared below, but the next post will go into detail on our survey results! </span>I analyzed these two sources of data to understand:</p>
<p><strong><em>Is the audience loyal to WBUR or not? Are they donors? Listeners? Not aware of WBUR?</em></strong></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If the audience already donates to WBUR, are they be willing to donate also to CitySpace?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If the audience is made up of WBUR listeners who do not donate, will attending CitySpace events encourage them to donate to WBUR or CitySpace? </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If the audience is unfamiliar with WBUR, could a separate CitySpace events membership make most sense for serving this unique audience.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><strong><em>Do people like CitySpace events? Are they returning to multiple events?</em></strong></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Can we increase the number of repeat attendees with a paid events membership?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">How can we encourage people to buy tickets to future events with ticket packages and come back?</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><b><i>Are event attendees public radio donors?</i></b></h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2013 alignright" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/image2-287x300.png" alt="" width="237" height="247" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/image2-287x300.png 287w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/image2.png 722w" sizes="(max-width: 237px) 100vw, 237px" /></p>
<p>On average, we found that 70% of ticket buyers are not WBUR donors. While some events attracted loyal WBUR listeners, many events were attracting outside audiences. With just qualitative observations to reflect on previously, this 70% number was surprising to the team. While they expected a large number of non-donors, they didn’t realize that almost three-quarters of ticket buyers were not “loyal” to WBUR.</p>
<p><i>WBUR has different membership levels for those who donate to the station: (1) </i><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Major donor, a one time gift more than $1,500, (2) </span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sustainer, a monthly donation of any amount, and (3) </span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Member, a one time donor of any amount less than $1,500.</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although the average is 70%, this percentage varies depending on the type of event. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Knowing which events attract which types of audiences can help set audience and attendance goals. For example, is your event for engaging and interacting with donors, or is it to attract new general public audiences? Ticket pricing and marketing should align to these goals. Events like our </span><a href="https://www.wbur.org/events/465181/the-handmaids-aria-how-an-iconic-novel-became-an-opera"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Handmaid’s Aria</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> attracted many WBUR donors than average because the team targeted marketing efforts at donors and the topic aligned to our listeners’ interest in the author Margaret Atwood. We knew the event would sell out quickly, so took this strong match of interest from our existing donors as an opportunity to charge a higher ticket price ($50). For the event </span><a href="https://www.wbur.org/events/445081/tackling-gun-violence"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tackling Gun Violence</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, our goal was to attract a diverse, community-focused audience, so we kept ticket prices low ($10) and marketed broadly across the city, without specifically targeting donors in our marketing. The resulting audience reflects this with few donors in attendance. </span></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Member-Ratios-at-3-Events.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-2021 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Member-Ratios-at-3-Events-1024x475.png" alt="" width="750" height="348" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Member-Ratios-at-3-Events-1024x475.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Member-Ratios-at-3-Events-300x139.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Member-Ratios-at-3-Events-768x356.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Member-Ratios-at-3-Events.png 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><b><i><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/image-4.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2012 alignright" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/image-4-300x266.png" alt="" width="295" height="262" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/image-4-300x266.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/image-4-768x681.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/image-4.png 918w" sizes="(max-width: 295px) 100vw, 295px" /></a>Are event attendees public radio listeners? </i></b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In our post-event survey, we asked “Had you heard of WBUR before today?” and we found that 46% of the survey respondents are WBUR listeners, but not donors. This showed that although most attendees are not donors, many of them are still listeners (42% + 46% = 88%). The survey showed a slight difference in non-donor numbers: 58% of survey respondents were non-donors as opposed to 74% non-donors from the ticket data. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><b><i>Do event attendees come to multiple events?</i></b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To sense if people are enjoying the new WBUR event space, I used our OvationTix ticket buyer data to see how many people bought tickets to multiple, different events and then if they attended them.</span></p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td><b># of ticket buyers who</b><b> bought</b><b> </b></td>
<td><b># of ticket buyers who </b><b>attended</b></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Total events</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">3728</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">2450</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>2 or more events</strong></td>
<td><strong>420</strong></td>
<td><strong>215</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>%</td>
<td>11.3%</td>
<td>8.8%</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Of all ticket buyers, 420 bought tickets to 2+ events, but only 215 of those ticket buyers attended 2+ events. This means that 11.3% of ticket buyers bought tickets to at least two event and 8.8% of ticket buyers have </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">attended </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">at least two events.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">(This only counts ticket buyers and does not count their guests, since we don’t know who their guests are each time. If we add in ticket buyers’ guests, the 215 attendees would increase, but we can’t know for sure that ticket buyers bring the same guests every time.)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now that CitySpace is reaching its sixth month of operation, the number of repeat attendees should begin to increase, and these percentages will be continued to be tracked. In the first few months, the low number of repeat attendees was promising in terms of new audience building. CitySpace was reaching new people with each event and building a large email list to increase awareness.</span></p>
<h3><b><i>Summary</i></b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overall, this analysis revealed several potential revenue opportunities to test for WBUR CitySpace: </span></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">With 70% of event attendees being non-donors, CitySpace can explore ways to convince these audience members to donate to WBUR CitySpace programming, supporting future events.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">For the 12% of event attendees who are not listeners or haven’t even heard of WBUR, there are fresh opportunities for increasing WBUR’s brand awareness, which can increase later ticket sales, listening audience, and donations to WBUR and CitySpace.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">With few repeat attendees, CitySpace can test different membership models now to encourage buying more tickets, through ticket packages or topic-based memberships.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Collecting and tracking this data on a repeat basis can help set goals for CitySpace, for example raising repeat attendees to a certain percent, or setting a revenue goal.</span></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Understanding your audience is an important step to identifying potential revenue streams. Factors that influence why people come to events affect how many people buy tickets, if they will come back and buy more tickets, or if they will consider donating. Are they coming because of your station? Do they care about supporting the station? Or are they coming for the topic or performer and wouldn’t care who hosted it? If you have information like audience data, donor data, emailing lists, or ticket sales, understanding your audience is the first step toward brainstorming potential revenue streams.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
