<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Brian Kelley &#8211; Public Radio Biz Lab</title>
	<atom:link href="/author/kelleybd/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 14:40:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/cropped-bizlab_round_wordmark_yellow-1-32x32.gif</url>
	<title>Brian Kelley &#8211; Public Radio Biz Lab</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Summer &#8217;19 BizLab Fellows: Takeaways from an Interview</title>
		<link>/2019/09/summer-19-bizlab-fellows-takeaways-from-an-interview/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Kelley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 01:53:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News from the Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BizLab Fellows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WBUR]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2205</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This summer, BizLab was joined by three fellows, each from different disciplines, academic levels, and areas of expertise. Matt Aufiero was BizLab’s Affiliate Marketing fellow, Sarah Barden its Cityspace fellow, and I was its Marketing and Promotions fellow. Before our last day, I was able to interview Matt and Sarah. This provided me with a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This summer, BizLab was joined by three fellows, each from different disciplines, academic levels, and areas of expertise. <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/matt-aufiero/">Matt Aufiero</a> was BizLab’s Affiliate Marketing fellow, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sbarden1/">Sarah Barden</a> its Cityspace fellow, and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/brian-kelley-33728b17a/">I</a> was its Marketing and Promotions fellow. Before our last day, I was able to interview Matt and Sarah. This provided me with a chance to compare and contrast our experiences here at WBUR.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The most common theme in our interview was how quickly we picked up on the unique world of public media. Working for a nonprofit media organization was new to all of us, but we were able to recognize the mission and sensibility right away. During our time with BizLab, each of us felt that we were able to expand our roles and learn about numerous opportunities within the industry. Not only did we have the ability to learn about the industry, but everyone we encountered was very supportive of the fellows. Everyone wanted to know how you were doing and wanted to help you find connections to further your career.</span></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Children-Develop-Foundational-Social-Emotional-Skills-1-e1476731419771.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2210 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Children-Develop-Foundational-Social-Emotional-Skills-1-e1476731419771-300x140.png" alt="" width="341" height="159" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Children-Develop-Foundational-Social-Emotional-Skills-1-e1476731419771-300x140.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Children-Develop-Foundational-Social-Emotional-Skills-1-e1476731419771-768x358.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Children-Develop-Foundational-Social-Emotional-Skills-1-e1476731419771.png 797w" sizes="(max-width: 341px) 100vw, 341px" /></a></p>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Matt:</strong> At BizLab, we can wear multiple hats and experience a few different things. I like that in a role, because I can learn more about other opportunities that I’d be interested in.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Sarah:</strong> It felt nice to be appreciated and I was happy to see my work influencing [the CitySpace team’s] decisions throughout the summer on how to incorporate my experiments into their work.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Brian:</strong> Seeing the span of the work that BizLab is doing and being able to help stations find revenue streams is something that I definitely appreciate. BizLab also has a supportive and welcoming environment that has been great to be part of.</span></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another trend was that we learned about the industry by jumping into topics that we didn’t have a ton of experience with. None of us had worked professionally in the media industry before our fellowships, and my experiences were limited to working in college radio.</span></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/1_ENgzTBvRp6OXiuejcGlZ-g.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2208 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/1_ENgzTBvRp6OXiuejcGlZ-g-300x172.png" alt="" width="315" height="181" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/1_ENgzTBvRp6OXiuejcGlZ-g-300x172.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/1_ENgzTBvRp6OXiuejcGlZ-g.png 698w" sizes="(max-width: 315px) 100vw, 315px" /></a></p>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Matt:</strong> I had never worked in the media industry before, so I needed to learn pretty quickly about what was acceptable in radio and what would be acceptable in public radio.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Sarah:</strong> I didn’t know anything about planning events, so being on a team where they’re doing that all the time, I learned a lot.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Brian:</strong> Going into the workshop with WLRN was interesting. It was my first day on the job and I was thrown right in, but it gave me a better idea of what we were doing at BizLab.</span></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Our last takeaway was that failure can actually be a good thing. This isn’t something that is typically accepted in many schools and businesses, but our BizLab experience really taught us about the positive side of hearing “no”.</span></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/do-you-learn-more-from-your-successes-than-from-your-failures.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2209 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/do-you-learn-more-from-your-successes-than-from-your-failures-300x169.png" alt="" width="302" height="170" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/do-you-learn-more-from-your-successes-than-from-your-failures-300x169.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/do-you-learn-more-from-your-successes-than-from-your-failures.png 620w" sizes="(max-width: 302px) 100vw, 302px" /></a></p>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Matt:</strong> I learned that a product doesn’t need to be perfect on the first try. Getting the product out there and testing it and trying to improve it from there is really important. If you are persistent and continue to work on your projects, you’ll get a result that you can tweak and improve upon.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Sarah:</strong> The lean startup method that BizLab uses is great and I don’t think I’ve ever experienced it in a non-profit environment before.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Brian:</strong> I’ve realized that you can learn from hearing “no” and that you can improve your product based on failures and roadblocks. There are steps that you can take to improve your product post-release, because it’s nearly impossible to satisfy 100% of your goal on the first try.</span></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Working at BizLab over the past summer has truly been a great experience for each of us. We learned about the lean startup method, how to grow our audience, how to implement experiments into real world situations, and that hearing “no” allows you to learn and improve over time. We developed connections and worked with people from WBUR, VPR, WDET, WLRN, LPM, DCist, and CapRadio. Lastly, we’d like to thank Lindsy Goldberg, Joan DiMicco, Ted Fuller, Sarah Bloomer, and Nancy Mann for welcoming us to the BizLab team and supporting us throughout the summer. Learning about the media industry and working with BizLab has been an incredible experience that none of us will soon forget.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_2211" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2211" style="width: 750px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-29-at-11.03.44-AM.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2211 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-29-at-11.03.44-AM-1024x600.png" alt="" width="750" height="439" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-29-at-11.03.44-AM-1024x600.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-29-at-11.03.44-AM-300x176.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-29-at-11.03.44-AM-768x450.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-29-at-11.03.44-AM.png 1089w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2211" class="wp-caption-text">The Summer 2019 BizLab team!</figcaption></figure>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thank you for reading Brian Kelley’s 3rd and final blog post as BizLab’s Summer Marketing and Promotions Fellow.</span></i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Organic vs Paid Posts on Social Media</title>
		<link>/2019/08/organic-vs-paid-posts-on-social-media/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Kelley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 19:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News from the Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BizLab Fellows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2120</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome to Brian Kelley’s second post as a BizLab fellow. This week’s topic is organic vs paid posts on social media. Every company wants to grow their consumer base, but some are unsure of how to successfully create growth. This is especially true when it comes to growing a social media following. In [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hello and welcome to Brian Kelley’s second post as a BizLab fellow. This week’s topic is organic vs paid posts on social media.</span></i></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Every company wants to grow their consumer base, but some are unsure of how to successfully create growth. This is especially true when it comes to growing a social media following. In this blog post, I will be discussing the differences between organic and paid social media, as well as the experiences I have had with each.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Organic posts are always free. In creating an organic post, you use the basic tools provided to you by Facebook, Twitter, or Instagram. With an organic post, the best way you can develop your community is by sharing information relevant to your product/mission and sharing it in a way that is visually or verbally stimulating to the audience.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a paid post, the person who wants to advertise the message will pay Facebook, Twitter, or Instagram to share their post with people who fit into a certain demographic. Paid posts work differently depending on which social media platform you are trying to use.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Paid Posts on Facebook</b></p>
<figure id="attachment_2177" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2177" style="width: 600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/facebook-business-manager-open-ads-manager.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2177 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/facebook-business-manager-open-ads-manager.png" alt="" width="600" height="282" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/facebook-business-manager-open-ads-manager.png 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/facebook-business-manager-open-ads-manager-300x141.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2177" class="wp-caption-text">Where to find the ad management page on Facebook Business Manager</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Facebook offers a large array of options when it comes to advertising. You can pay for an ad or boost an existing post. A boosted post is aimed simply at clicks and general engagement, while an advertisement offers several more-sophisticated objectives to choose from. These objectives are broken down into three different categories: awareness, consideration, and conversion. With an “awareness” ad, your objectives would fall under creating brand awareness and reaching a larger number of people. Traffic and engagement would fall under the “consideration” category. Lastly, a “conversion” ad aims to create sales and store visits.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A boosted post will have a different outcome than a standard Facebook ad. Choosing an ad instead of a boosted post will be a be better for most companies, as a boosted post will only increase general site engagement rather than generating sales or collecting email addresses. Additionally, a boosted post will only last for a maximum of seven days. If your goals are more specific than simple engagement, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">like generating store traffic, conversions, and leads, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">a boosted post will not be as effective as an ad.</span></p>
<p><b>Paid Posts on Instagram</b></p>
<figure id="attachment_2123" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2123" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/instagram-ads-create-promotion-destination-e1565962724727.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2123 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/instagram-ads-create-promotion-destination-e1565962724727.png" alt="" width="300" height="533" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/instagram-ads-create-promotion-destination-e1565962724727.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/instagram-ads-create-promotion-destination-e1565962724727-169x300.png 169w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2123" class="wp-caption-text">The page to create a promoted Instagram post</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Instagram was purchased by Facebook in April of 2012, so the two platforms utilize the same ad management program. However, Instagram users are typically a much younger demographic, with a majority of users being between the ages of 15-29. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Like Facebook, you can pay for two different formats of instagram advertising known as “promoted” or “sponsored” posts. A promoted post on Instagram will operate similarly to a boosted post on Facebook, as even though it is easier to put out, you will only be reaching a very narrow group of people. A sponsored post will require the user to utilize Facebook’s ad manager, but you will be able to select objectives, demographics, budgets, and a “run time” for your ad. Having the ability to choose these options will likely result in a more successful ad campaign.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With Instagram advertising, advertisers are able to reach a large number of people and create brand awareness. Advertisers are more able to customize their advertisements on Instagram because you have more goal-oriented and demographic options available to you. However, in order to properly advertise on Instagram, you must utilize Facebook to access the ad manager. Advertising on Instagram is a great way to reach the age 15-29 demographic, but if you are aiming for a more mature audience, a Facebook campaign may be more effective.</span></p>
<p><b>Paid Posts on Twitter</b></p>
<figure id="attachment_2122" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2122" style="width: 429px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-16-at-9.28.12-AM.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2122 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-16-at-9.28.12-AM.png" alt="" width="429" height="551" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-16-at-9.28.12-AM.png 429w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-16-at-9.28.12-AM-234x300.png 234w" sizes="(max-width: 429px) 100vw, 429px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2122" class="wp-caption-text">The page to create sponsored Twitter content</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On Twitter, paid posts are referred to as “sponsored content”. You can choose a particular tweet from your account that you’d like to promote. You set the location and the budget for your post and Twitter optimizes the message based on your budget and the demographic information of your account.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some of the upsides to advertising on Twitter are that you can drive traffic to your Twitter page and website and that Twitter utilizes a very cost effective method of “price per click”. The issue with promoting on Twitter is that it can be difficult for small accounts. Promoted tweets disappear if their engagement rate is too low. Additionally, Twitter does not allow you to choose a goal for the campaign, which could impact your personal success rate for the paid tweet.</span></p>
<p><b>BizLab’s Experiences and Data</b></p>
<figure id="attachment_2124" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2124" style="width: 599px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-16-at-9.42.05-AM.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2124 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-16-at-9.42.05-AM.png" alt="" width="599" height="436" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-16-at-9.42.05-AM.png 599w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-16-at-9.42.05-AM-300x218.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 599px) 100vw, 599px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2124" class="wp-caption-text">BizLab&#8217;s Twitter Homepage</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">During my time at BizLab, I have used only organic posts for our Twitter account. Our number of followers is up by almost 25% and our number of impressions has greatly increased.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Additionally, BizLab team members Ted Fuller and Matt Aufiero ran an <a href="/2019/08/exploring-the-potential-of-affiliate-marketing-the-challenge/">affiliate marketing project</a> on Facebook this summer and were able to share some of their data with me. <a href="https://www.hubspot.com/">Hubspot</a>, is a developer and marketer of software products for inbound marketing and sales. They reported that the average CPM or “cost per 1K impressions” was approximately $7.00. The affiliate marketing project operated by BizLab this summer had a CPM of $10.74. This is a high CPM compared to industry standards, but the overage was caused by us targeting very specific audiences. Hubspot also reported that the average CTR or “click through rate” was .99%. The affiliate marketing project recorded a 2.87% CTR. This is a high click through rate for a Facebook ad, but it may be due to our specific audience or the quality of the products that were being advertised. Lastly, our median cost per landing page view for the affiliate marketing project was $0.56 (ranging as high as $4.29 and as low as $0.11). Unfortunately, Hubspot does not provide benchmark data on the median cost per landing page view. Ultimately, we were able to reach over 850,000 Facebook users, but only 111 users purchased a product that we had advertised.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of our cohort stations, <a href="https://wdet.org/">WDET</a>, is experimenting with Instagram advertising. They have been reaching out to Detroit’s local businesses and partnering with them, which brings local businesses onto WDET’s Instagram page. Thus far, local businesses have been excited and willing to pay for the opportunity to have an ad posted on WDET’s Instagram page. WDET’s existing audience is loving the local content and click/engagement rates have been high.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If your goal is to increase or maintain general activity on your site, then boosting or promoting a post on Instagram or Facebook is the way to go. However, in most cases, paying for a full ad on any social media site will be the more effective method. By paying for an ad, you can select a specific goal for your campaign and you can highlight more demographic factors. While you’re posting ads, it is important to respond to comments so that users feel as though they are listened to and do not feel as though they are following a purely ad based account. Finding balance between organic posts, responding to potential customers and users, and selecting the proper method of promotion are vital to the success of a social media campaign.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>BizLab&#8217;s Twitter Outreach and Analytics</title>
		<link>/2019/08/intro-to-twitter-analytics-blog-post/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Kelley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 20:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News from the Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BizLab Fellows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1795</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Topic: How we have increased our outreach through BizLab’s Twitter account Hello and welcome to my first blog on the BizLab site! My name is Brian Kelley and I was hired as BizLab’s marketing and promotions summer fellow in early June. I am a Communications major and will be going into my senior year at [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Topic:</strong> How we have increased our outreach through BizLab’s Twitter account</span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hello and welcome to my first blog on the BizLab site! My name is Brian Kelley and I <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/0.jpeg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignleft wp-image-1836 size-thumbnail" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/0-150x150.jpeg" alt="" width="150" height="150" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/0-150x150.jpeg 150w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/0.jpeg 184w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /></a>was hired as BizLab’s marketing and promotions summer fellow in early June. I am a Communications major and will be going into my senior year at <a href="https://www.merrimack.edu/">Merrimack College</a> beginning in September. Since I was hired, I have been observing and learning about the media industry through my experiences and interactions with BizLab. In this blog, I will be discussing the methods and data that have played a role in increasing our social media following on Twitter.</span></em></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the first things that I did when I was hired was to check the previous activity of the account. The activity of the account was vital to check, as it provided me with a more precise idea of the account’s objectives, previous tweets, and analytics. Our Twitter page, <a href="https://twitter.com/WBURBizLab">@WBURBizLab</a>, was created in October of 2018. As of June 1, we had 231 followers and our tweets had reached 33,200 people. Not a bad number, but something that could be improved upon. In order to discover our strengths and potential areas of improvement, I dove deeper into each individual tweet to find successful trends.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_1935" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1935" style="width: 516px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://twitter.com/WBURBizLab"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1935" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-30-at-3.25.35-PM.png" alt="" width="516" height="413" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1935" class="wp-caption-text">The homepage of @WBURBizLab on Twitter</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One positive trend that I noticed was when tweets mentioned specific organizations. A January 9th tweet congratulated <a href="http://dcist.com/">DCist</a>, <a href="https://louisvillepublicmedia.org/">LPM</a>, <a href="http://wlrn.org/">WLRN</a>, <a href="http://vpr.org/">VPR</a>, <a href="http://capradio.org/">CapRadio</a>, and <a href="http://wdet.org/">WDET</a> and tagged each of them by using @ and the station. This post generated 1500 views, 11 likes, and 2 retweets. By tagging each station, we increased the likelihood that the message would be seen by individuals who follow the station, but do not yet follow the @WBURBizLab account.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_1928" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1928" style="width: 453px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-25-at-12.57.57-PM.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1928 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-25-at-12.57.57-PM-e1564514038912.png" alt="" width="453" height="154" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1928" class="wp-caption-text">A successful Tweet from January 9, 2019 tagged each cohort station</figcaption></figure>
<p>Another key practice was the inclusion of hashtags. In the time prior to me joining BizLab, there was only one tweet that included a hashtag. The January 11th tweet included the hashtag #pubmedia, which is one of the main identifiers used by public media organizations on Twitter. The tweet generated 2,724 views and can be directly tied to an increase of 4 followers.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1930" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1930" style="width: 444px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-25-at-12.59.13-PM.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1930" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-25-at-12.59.13-PM.png" alt="" width="444" height="124" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-25-at-12.59.13-PM.png 430w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-25-at-12.59.13-PM-300x84.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 444px) 100vw, 444px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1930" class="wp-caption-text">This post used the hashtag #pubmedia, which is one of the more successful &#8220;impression getters&#8221; for the public media industry</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lastly, I found that tweets that included photos would typically increase impressions and followers for our account. For example, there was a media tweet from March that read “We kicked off our first 2019 station workshop with @DCist/@WAMU885 today. We are spending 3 intense days summarizing research, ideating product offerings, and designing lean tests of our ideas. AKA lots of stickies” generated 3,833 impressions. These 3,833 impressions represented over 90% of BizLab’s total Twitter outreach for the month.</span></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/download-1.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1960 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/download-1.jpg" alt="" width="480" height="361" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To summarize, I found that tagging accounts, including hashtags, and using media (photo or gif) posts has worked for us in the past. By including these more throughout June and July,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> our following is up to 284 people from 231, which means that we have increased our follower count by about 23% since June 1. Additionally, we have made roughly 13,800 impressions over the past 61 days, which represents 42% of our total from our account’s inception date through May 31st. Tweets from January-mid June are no longer receiving as many views, but tweets from late June- today are still generating impressions, so the 13,800 generated since June 1 will likely increase in the coming days.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_1949" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1949" style="width: 600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-08-01-at-11.48.57-AM.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1949 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-08-01-at-11.48.57-AM.png" alt="" width="600" height="371" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-08-01-at-11.48.57-AM.png 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-08-01-at-11.48.57-AM-300x186.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1949" class="wp-caption-text">23.2K from January 1st &#8211; May 31st, 13.8K from June 1st- July 31st</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For more on BizLab, follow us on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/WBURBizLab">@WBURBizLab</a> or consider subscribing to our monthly newsletter.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
